<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <description>Cloudify is an open source application and network orchestration framework based on TOSCA that supports hybrid cloud deployments bridging public and private environments.</description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 14:36:21 +0300</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 14:36:21 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.4.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Organizations Use Orchestration to Automate Their Splunk Deployments</title>
        <description>&lt;notextile&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/cloudify-splunk-automation-scale.png&quot; alt=&quot;Cloudify Splunk Automation and Orchestration at Scale&quot; width=&quot;870&quot;&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;As more and more organizations today turn to Splunk for their log management and monitoring capabilities, deploying large scale Splunk environments has gotten more and more time consuming. In turn this wastes precious engineering resources, as more and more of these resources are used for manual actions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;In this on-demand webinar, Risk Focus, noted experts in Trading, Risk Management &amp;amp; Cloud Transformation, tackle the subject, and explain how they are leveraging &lt;a href=&quot;/product&quot;&gt;cloud orchestration&lt;/a&gt; to automate this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;They explain why automation is not only the fast way to do this, but also why using automation for these splunk deployments also offers enhanced security, and is way less prone to human errors. We discuss some of the challenges that Splunk adaption leaves us with, especially in terms of scalability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;Also discussed is a real life use case, where one of the largest banks in North America is using this solution to create massive amounts of log data, which helps ensure that they are compliant with its internal security regulations, auditing trails, meeting retention requirements for ephemeral infrastructure, along with creating accessible log backups. This use case is already being used at the bank, provisioning over 12,000 VM&#39;s, all of which are monitored by Splunk in the cloud service layer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We cover our belief that Splunk can be treated in the same way that infrastructure as code, and how this methodology can change the way you deploy splunk or any other application at scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the questions and topics that are discussed include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Did this deployment include Splunk Enterprise Security, if so, what were the challenges compared to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.splunk.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Splunk&lt;/a&gt; Core?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How did you separate the system based Apps vs. user based Apps/config and yet keep it all under version control?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are Splunk upgrades handled through the same level of automation?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are there plans to support other clouds or containers?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How is &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;Cloudify&lt;/a&gt; different from any &lt;span&gt;cloud&lt;/span&gt; orchestration solution?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How was autoscaling configured?  Is &lt;span&gt;Cloudify&lt;/span&gt; doing it?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is the Salt configuration triggered from within &lt;span&gt;Cloudify&lt;/span&gt; via plugins, or some other way?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have you implemented Cloudify in a &lt;a href=&quot;/why/&quot;&gt;Hybrid Cloud Environment&lt;/a&gt;? If yes, what kind of challenges have you faced?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Register below to watch this webinar on demand! Registrants also receive a example blueprint which can be used with Cloudify for evaluating how this Splunk automation is actually used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also learned from our audience how many are already using Splunk or planning to use it in the future, that 16% of our viewers are already using the machine learning capabilities of Splunk, what the primary use-case for Splunk is (log aggregation reigns supreme), and how many people have a multi-node Splunk cluster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Register to watch&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;container&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;span2&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;span5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;hubspot-form&quot;&gt;&lt;script charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; type=&quot;text/javascript&quot; src=&quot;//js.hsforms.net/forms/v2.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;script&gt;
hbspt.forms.create({
    portalId: &#39;1918719&#39;,
    formId: &#39;6501a8d9-5c17-4a4d-a866-3183ad26f8a3&#39;,
    target: &#39;.hubspot-form&#39;,
    onFormSubmit: function ($form) {
        dataLayer.push({
            &#39;event&#39;: &#39;GAevent&#39;,
            &#39;eventCategory&#39;: &#39;Form Completion&#39;,
            &#39;eventAction&#39;: &#39;Submitted Splunk Webinar Form&#39;,
            &#39;eventLabel&#39;: &#39;Splunk Automation Webinar&#39;
        })
    }
});
&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;span5&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This webinar is part of our &lt;a href=&quot;/webinars&quot;&gt;webinar series&lt;/a&gt;. Our webinar series tackles everything from using Cloudify for &lt;a href=&quot;/webinars/devops-data-intensive-applications-webinar.html&quot;&gt;rapidly deploying data intensive applications&lt;/a&gt;, using Cloudify orchestration as part of an &lt;a href=&quot;/webinars/open-vCPE-framework-webinar.html&quot;&gt;Open vCPE solution&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;/webinars/monolith-to-microservices-webinar.html&quot;&gt;moving software architecture from monolithic to microservices oriented design&lt;/a&gt;, and even &lt;a href=&quot;/webinar/edge-computing-webinar&quot;&gt;orchestration in the age of edge computing&lt;/a&gt;. Feel free to watch any of our previous webinars &quot;on-demand&quot; here, and be sure to register for future webinars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/notextile&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>/2017/07/27/how-organizations-use-orchestration-automate-splunk-deployments.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2017/07/27/how-organizations-use-orchestration-automate-splunk-deployments.html</guid>
        
        <category>Cloud Orchestration</category>
        
        <category>Splunk</category>
        
        <category>Big Data</category>
        
        <category>TOSCA</category>
        
        <category>Cloud Management</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Birth of an Edge Orchestrator - Cloudify Meets Egde Computing</title>
        <description>&lt;notextile&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/cloudify-orchestration-master-edge.png&quot; alt=&quot;Cloudify mobile edge orchestration&quot; width=&quot;870&quot;&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many claim that it&amp;rsquo;s the &lt;a href=&quot;https://a16z.com/2016/12/16/the-end-of-cloud-computing/&quot;&gt;end of the cloud computing&lt;/a&gt; [Peter Levin] as we are familiar with it today. That doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean that the cloud world will end tomorrow, but it means that cloud computing is going to change drastically from a centralized cloud to many distributed autonomous local clouds, or, move to the edge. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/edge-data-center-opnfv-pharos.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The motivation for such a move stems from the fact that the requirements are evolving at a very fast pace - IoT, connected cars, smart cities, connected airplanes, ships, drones, etc. Lots of data is generated &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;at the edge and real-time decisions need to be made locally, and not in one centralized place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The central cloud still exists, but it serves as a &amp;ldquo;learning center&amp;rdquo; where data analytics is gathered from all the local edge clouds so that interesting events and applied actions can be shared among the local edge clouds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oNK-k0KvDBY&quot;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt; is a talk that I gave no this topic at the OpenStack Day Israel 2017 event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many other names for edge cloud such as cloud in a box, datacenter in a box, edge data center, uCPE as an edge cloud, cloudlets and many more to come. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pullquote-left&quot;&gt;
  &lt;font style=&quot;font-weight: bold&quot; size=&quot;5&quot; face=&quot;Baskerville Old Face&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Read the full vCPE/SD-WAN White Paper.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/font&gt;  &lt;a class=&quot;btn btn-medium btn-theme btn-rounded&quot; id=&quot;downloadBtnInner&quot; href=&quot;/whitepapers/vcpe-sdwan-network-orchestration?utm_campaign=vcpe%20white%20paper&amp;utm_source=website_blogs_jh&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;icon-plus&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Go &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  
  &lt;hr&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/cloudlets.png&quot; width=&quot;600&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aligncenter&quot; style=&quot;font-size: 12px&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;InfoWorld - Cloudlets: Where the cloud meets intelligent devices&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazon (AWS) is coming out with their own version of an edge cloud enabler - &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/greengrass/&quot;&gt;Greengrass&lt;/a&gt; - which provides embedded Lambda serverless compute for connected local devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The emergence of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mobile_edge_computing&quot;&gt;MEC&lt;/a&gt; (mobile edge computing) and 5G are furthering the adoption of local edge computing. An example of edge platform hardware from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.opnfv.org/community/projects/pharos&quot;&gt;OPNFV Pharos&lt;/a&gt; project is shown above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More and more examples of cheap edge data centers built on ARM processors or even Raspberry PI are emerging. 